Satwik Mohanty

Big Data Analyst

Big Data analyst working at Infosys for Apple making the experience of Apple Mac and Iphone users better u. Exploring Web Technologies MEAN and MERN stack with little experience in AI. Tech-Stack=[PySpark, Spark, HDFS, Singlestore, MongoDB, NLP, Deep-learning, HTML, CSS, Javascript, Kafka, Python, UNIX, Bash, cron]

+918455824391

India

linkedin.com/in/satwik-mohanty-952367169

quora.com/profile/Satwik-Mohanty-6

github.com/satwikskm

stackoverflow.com/users/14982409/satwik-mohanty

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Technology in Electrical Engineering,

C.V Raman College of Engineering

08/2017 - 06/2021

CGPA: 8.61

SKILLS



WORK EXPERIENCE

System Engineer

Infosys Limited 09/2021 - Present

Bhubaneswar DC

Responsibilities

- Development of Python and Bash based application for Automation and verification
- Tuning of Queries and Optimise memory useaage in Database
- Handling tickets for various units P1,P2,P3
- Maintaining various Clusters and Application hosted inside it
- Database upgrade testing
- Deploying python scripts at server
- Automation of ETL tasks using Python

DBbench and Tdbench

Single Store Development for Apple Users (09/2021 - Present)

Spark and Pyspark based data analytics

System Engineer Trainee

Infosys Limited 06/2021 - 09/2021

Mysore DC

Responsibility

- Unix and its application
- Data processsing using Scala
- Hadoop and Hive based analytics
- Spark based analytics using scala
- No Sql Database(MongoDB)
- Data Analytics using Hive

Machine Learning Intern **Foreignadmits**

06/2020 - 10/2020

Work from home

An Edutech consultancy specialized in career counselling foreign university .

Responsibility

- Scrapped university data to prepare a dataset.
- Used it to prepare API for a tool named university predictor.
- Designed a NLP powered tool to analyze and access the Statement of Purpose and suggest the errors.
- Received Letter of Recommendation from the founders.
- Documenting all projects

Big Data application for Singlestore

Decreased query execution time significantly by 50%

PROJECTS EXPERIENCE

- Project experience on database optimisation, pool allocation
- Providing fast Web/UI dashboard for Apple Client
- Tableau Dashboard
- Python based automation
- Database upgrade testing

Singlestore Automated Data Analytics (03/2022 - Present)

- Using Memsql to gather high volume memory and disk table
- Raising an automated Alert via email using Python and Bash / Unix
- Setting a Cron job to run it at regular interval
- It also clears the backup and unused stage table thus keeping the cluster healthy

Agriculture using Efficient technology

- Artificial Intelligence based agricultural system hooked with sensors to monitor and act on real time environment with web interface and community support
- Machine learning based Sensor Data analysis and report generation

ACHIEVEMENTS

AICTE Chhatra Viswakarma Awards 2019

Received Scroll of Honour from MHRD ministry and AICTE for works in the field of value addition to Rural Handicraft and Agro products

Infosys Insta Award 2021